<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>BLOG_NAME</title>
 <link href="YOUR_URL/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="YOUR_URL"/>
 <updated>2013-08-15T20:47:55-07:00</updated>
 <id>BLOG_URL</id>
 <author>
   <name>BLOG_NAME</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Stop shooting by yourself</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/how-many-times.html"/>
   <updated>2013-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/how-many-times</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When you're looking to get extra work in do you take a bag of balls out and go shoot for an hour? You shouldn't.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a striker, on a good day, you take probably 7-8 shots at goal. There are a number of other things you do far more often in a game that you should be working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;426&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/e4pr40rue_A&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


&lt;p&gt;How many first touches do you take? How many 1v1 situations do you get in? How many passes do you make? How many tackles? How often do you call for the ball? How many runs should you be making? How many turns?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;yThere are plenty of other things you do more often in a game that you should work on perfecting. Things that happen over and over again in a 90 min match. And when you get good enough at those other things a goal is nothing more than a pass into the back of the net anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cutting off the ankle guards</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/cutting-off-the-ankle-guards.html"/>
   <updated>2013-08-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/cutting-off-the-ankle-guards</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I was in college we had this Police Officer that would come to the gym the same time as us for weight training. Officer Packer was the real deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time we saw Packer doing squats, hang cleans, military press or even jumping on the box he was in full gear. That means boots, badge, gun, pants, flashlight, the whole lot. We knew him well so we knew why he did it, but whenever somebody asked him why he was in full gear, the response was always the same-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;When I'm out on the job I won't be in basketball shorts and a tank top, I'll be in full uniform. So, it makes sense to train that way.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you're training keep everything as close to game day as possible. Whether it's wearing shinguards, LOUD communication, listening to your ipod when putting on your boots, a focused warm-up or the pre-game handshake with your outside back. 'Train with your shinguards' isn't just a literal translation, it's your state of mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Yoga pants and cancer cells</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/yoga-pants-and-caner-cells.html"/>
   <updated>2013-08-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/yoga-pants-and-caner-cells</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today my neighbor told me she was going to yoga and I said yoga's not for me, it's too slow. Her response, &quot; Oh I'd much rather run up and down a field chasing a black and white ball.&quot; hmm...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every American soccer player gets to a point in their life where defending their sport is no longer enjoyable but exhausting. Some people just don't get it or don't want to. Besides you can dumb down anything using her formula-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yoga- &quot;Oh I'd much rather be in a flatulent filled room with a bunch of sweaty people..&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Riding a roller coaster- &quot;Oh I'd much rather have my hair all messed up while someone potentially vomits on me..&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curing Cancer- &quot;Oh, I'd much rather stare in a tiny microscope all day, squinting at unregulated oncogenes..&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't particularly like playing American football or baseball, but I can certainly appreciate the mental chess match between a pitcher and batter top six with 2 outs and a runner on 3rd, or the beauty in execution needed to drive the football 80 yds downfield with 4 min left in the fourth quarter. And yes, even the meditative introspection yoga demands.
She got me thinking how I would describe soccer if it wasn't just running up and down a field chasing a ball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, (when it's played the right way) it really is poetry in motion. It's all the instruments in a symphony playing to the same tune. It's a blank canvas for each artist to express their individual creativity. Every game is a chance to author a new book and no two stories are ever the same. It's an escape where literally, nothing else matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Nobody listens to their coach during the game (2/2)</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/nobody-listens-to-their-coach-during-the-game-2.html"/>
   <updated>2013-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/nobody-listens-to-their-coach-during-the-game-2</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If players, don't listen to their coach then what is the role of a coach? I like the term manager or boss that other countries seem to use to define this position. They are there to empower a player that must be responsive to what the game calls for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does miCoach help to enable that? &quot;Hey Quigsie, I see here that your total distance for the match was only 5.9 miles, as a Striker that's not good enough, I need you to work harder.&quot; Yelling this from the sideline would be utterly ridiculous. But, does communicating that after the match add value and empower the player?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quigsie takes this feedback and runs his face off the next game. His total mile count for this game was 8.2 miles. His coach is still unhappy, &quot;Coach, I did what you asked...&quot;
The issue with data is and has always been making sense of the data we do have, rather than continuing to accumulate more and more data points. Quigsie famously quits after he loses the ball up top and every time that happens the opposing team is able to start their counter-attack much easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My fear is miCoach data will help mask some of the intricacies of the game with it's &quot;analysis&quot; and it will become a crutch of sorts for coaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Hey Quigsie, I need you to work hard to win the ball back after you lose it up top. Every time you don't work hard to win it back it leaves the rest of the team out to dry.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://youtu.be/o1TWEoSmRwU?t=17m29s&quot;&gt;Listen to what Klinsman said about this exact sentiment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Parents and the american game</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/parents-and-the-american-game.html"/>
   <updated>2013-07-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/parents-and-the-american-game</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When trying to understand why the American game is so far behind other countries it can be useful to dissect all facets of the game/culture beyond the actual 90 min.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, it's become clear that American youth soccer coaches spend a significant amount of their time, attention and energy appeasing the parents of their players. &quot;Why didn't my kid play today? What were you thinking with that lineup? We haven't won in 4 games why are we paying all this money?&quot; and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven't thoroughly researched it, but I'm willing to bet most other successful footballing nations don't have this same issue.
The need to appease parents isn't there overseas and parents are less inclined to question a manager of their 13 yr old at AC Milan, because well, they're Milan.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Nobody listens to their coach during the game (1/2)</title>
   <link href="YOUR_URL/nobody-listens-to-their-coach-during-the-game.html"/>
   <updated>2013-07-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
   <id>BLOG_URL/nobody-listens-to-their-coach-during-the-game</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2012/07/19/adidas-micoach-elite-system-major-league-soccer/&quot;&gt;Adidas miCoach Soccer Elite Real-Time Smart System&lt;/a&gt; has become increasingly popular among soccer clubs to analyze and improve player performance. Basically, players wear chips that measure time, avg speed, max speed, distance, high-intensity distance, and number of sprints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is then streamed to the coaches, on the sideline in real-time.
Obviously, the thought of any one of the coaching staff looking down at an electronic device the whole game and then making &quot;real-time&quot; decisions based on these numbers is pretty sickening. But this raises a bigger issue for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/j4q503AbvsaUp4GXRjkDmEh-ClMBuHE3Zj76AFi3Lct_wm6Tw8PGMs6xB2u6F60PRccrwJef_AWI2iq4JqZh1NzZziwmIBEk5NWITlqsVj7jw6QySuMBStWv&quot; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody ever really listens to their coach when they're on the field. You listen to the game. Sure, you have a general strategy communicated by the coach before the game, but part of the beauty in soccer is there aren't X's and O's for every imaginable scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game demands creativity and that is something you can't hear from your coach on the sideline and certainly something you can't gather from a data sheet. At least not from the data sheet miCoach provides...&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>